地          球          脉          动
辽阔的草原
Vast open plains.
广袤无垠
Immense spaces.
万籁俱寂
Eerie silence.
然而 你若以为这里死气沉沉就大错特错了
But any feeling of emptiness is an illusion.
草原维系了我们行星最丰富多彩的生命群落
The plains of our planet support the greatest gatherings of wildlife on Earth.
这一切最终都依赖于一种生命体的存在
At the heart of all that happens here is a single living thing.
草
Grass.
这种神奇的植物覆盖了地球上四分之一的土地
This miraculous plant covers a quarter of all the lands of the Earth.
辽       阔       草       原
草地无所不在 一点雨水虽然不足以维系一片森林 却可使一片草地存活下来
Grasslands exist wherever there is a little rain, but not enough to sustain a forest.
画 外 音
大卫 · 爱登堡   爵士
有些草原非常辽阔
Some are huge.
仅中亚的疏树大草原
The Central Asian Steppe alone
便横跨了地球的三分之一
extends one third of the way around our planet.
在夏天 雄鹰可以毫不费力的在热气流上盘旋
It's summer, and eagles effortlessly cruise the thermals,
搜寻地上猎物的踪迹
scanning the ground beneath for signs of prey.
在遥远的外蒙古大草原
In the distant reaches of outer Mongolia,
地球上规模最大的迁徙大军正浩浩荡荡地行进着
one of the planet's great migrations is underway.
这一蔚为壮观的场面一年一次 但却很少有人亲眼目睹
Few people ever see this extraordinary annual event.
蒙古瞪羚
Mongolian gazelle.
共约两百万只瞪羚生活在此处 但具体数量仍不得知
Two million are thought to live here, but no one really knows.
瞪羚在大部分时间里 都各自流浪在这片广袤的大地上
For much of the time, they're scattered through this vast landscape,
然而 每年总有一次 这些它们将会聚集在一起 繁衍后代
but once a year they come together to have their young.
在接下来的十天之内 几乎所有的小家伙都会呱呱坠地
Nearly all will give birth within the next 10 days.
在毫无遮挡的草原上若想安全地繁衍 最佳方法是集体照看
0ut in the open, communal calving is the safest way to have young.
有了这么多双警惕的眼睛
With so many pairs of eyes keeping watch,
瞪羚们能够极其有效地防止自己遭到偷袭
it's almost impossible for predators to sneak up.
这里没有矮小的灌木 也没高大的乔木 只有一样东西可以藏身其后
There are no bushes, no trees. There's only one thing to hide behind.
草
Grass.
草的掩护并不是非常有效
And it's not very effective.
掠食动物在这片空旷的草地上繁衍后代也并不轻松
Predators also have a hard time raising their young on open grassland.
没有了树,鹰只能直接把巢安在地面上
Without trees, eagles have to nest directly on the ground.
所有生活在草原上的动物 都必须面对大自然残酷的一面
All the inhabitants of the Great Plains are exposed to the elements.
冲天的火光引起了一片恐慌
Fire sparks panic in the herd.
瞪羚是天生的跑步能手, 即使是小瞪羚 奔跑速度也快过火势蔓延的速度
Gazelles are born to run and even young calves easily outpace the flames,
前提条件是它们没有被困住
if they can avoid being trampled.
一路无阻的大火 无情地吞噬了一切无力逃跑的生灵
With nothing to stand in its way, the blaze consumes anything that can't flee.
大量的青草 宝贵的食物,片刻之间便化为乌有
Huge quantities of grass, valuable food, have been lost.
难逃一劫的还有老弱动物
And with it, the old and the weak.
瞪羚们远离了这片狼籍不堪的荒芜之地 继续行进 寻找新的草原
The gazelles move on to new pastures and leave the desolation behind them.
宛如从灰烬中复活的凤凰
From the ashes rises the phoenix.
草又匪夷所思地复活了
Grass, the incredible survivor.
草茎的基部有很强的自我保护能力
Because it grows from a protected part at the base of its stems,
几乎可以说 草是坚不可摧的
grass is almost indestructible.
草能迅速地自我修复 繁殖能力极强 在所有植物中 既是覆盖地球面积最大的
Able to repair and reproduce itself rapidly, it covers more of the Earth's land than any other plant
又是维系生命群落种类最多的
and feeds more wildlife than any other.
红嘴奎利亚雀
Red-billed quelea.
以15亿的数量聚集在非洲的稀树大草原上
0ne and a half billion swarm across the savannahs of Africa.
这些鸟是地球上数量最多的鸟
These are the most numerous birds on Earth.
这些鸟数量众多 让它们从你的头顶上飞过要花5个小时
Some flocks are so vast that they can take five hours to pass overhead.
只有草才能满足这些鸟的胃口
0nly grass can feed plagues of these proportions.
饥肠辘辘的群鸟贪婪地吞食着草的种子
The ravenous hordes devour the seeds.
而叶子和茎则被巨大的羚羊群所享受
And the leaves and stems are cropped by great herds of antelope.
仅生活在东非稀树大草原的角马 就接近两百万（注：角马属羚羊的一种）
The East African savannahs alone sustain nearly two million wildebeest.
这些角马拼命地吃草 把草根上面的草茎部分全部吃掉
They trim the grass down to its roots, leaving little in their wake,
然而被吃掉的那部分仅在数天之内就能恢复生长
but within days the plant will recover
草便又继续维系着地球上 最大的动物群落的食物需要
and continue to sustain the biggest herds on Earth.
草不仅生长在热带地区
Grass is not confined to the tropics.
即使在北极这样恶劣的环境下草也有办法生存下来
It manages to grow even in the bitter conditions of the Arctic.
在最后一批树木以外的地方, 处处是冰天雪地 一片荒芜
Beyond the limits of the last tree, the planet is barren and ice-locked.
那是地球边缘 天寒地冻 人迹罕至
A frozen no-man's land at the end of the Earth.
每年却总有短短的一阵日子 漫长阴暗的冬天也会放松它的钳制
But for a short time each year, the long, dark winter releases its grip.
温度回升 整个寒冬都在冬眠的草
Temperatures rise
又开始发芽
and grass that has lain dormant and frozen throughout the winter sprouts once more.
北极又披上了绿色的外衣
Green returns to the Arctic.
眼前是一片无边无际的平原 面积相当于一个澳大利亚
The receding ice reveals an immense flat plain the size of Australia.
这便是北极的苔原
This is the Arctic tundra.
虽然此时是万籁俱寂,一片荒凉的景象
It's a desolate, silent wilderness.
但这一切即将发生变化
But it's about to change.
雪雁
Snow geese.
它们在墨西哥湾越冬 等到春天便一路飞过北美洲 来到这里的北极苔原
They winter along the Gulf of Mexico, and in spring they fly the entire length of North America to reach the Arctic tundra.
每年有五百万只雪雁都是这样迁徙
Five million birds make this journey every year.
这场马拉松式的迁徙长达三千英里
Their marathon migration is almost 3,000 miles long
耗时多达三个多月
and has taken them three months.
虽然早己精疲力竭 饥肠辘辘 但它们终于返回了北极圈
Exhausted and starving, they touch down inside the Arctic Circle,
返回了它们阔别已久的繁殖地
back at their traditional breeding grounds at last.
雪雁一生只忠于一个配偶
Snow geese pair for life.
一对雪雁来了之后就必须取得自己的筑巢地
As soon as couples arrive, they must stake a claim to a nesting patch.
理想的地方寥寥无几,邻里纠纷时常发生
Ideal sites are in short supply and quarrelsome neighbours are all around.
有时闹得杀气腾腾
Disputes can be vicious.
方才罢休
Point taken!
北极的苔原虽然路途遥远, 但仍有短短的一段时间是食草动物的天堂
It's a long way to travel, but for a short period, the tundra is the ideal place for a grazer.
在这短暂夏日 草儿茁壮生长
The grass grows vigorously during the short, intense summer
而且这里的掠食动物比南方少多了
and there are fewer predators than further south.
在这里 雪雁可以比较放心地把巢筑在地上
Here, geese can nest on the ground in relative safety.
然而 雌雪雁必须花三周的时间孵蛋
Nonetheless, this female must incubate her eggs for three weeks
而在这三周里 它将变得易受攻击
and throughout this time she will be very vulnerable.
一头北极狐在雪雁的领地附近逡巡
An Arctic fox surveys the colony.
它已经等了整整一个冬天
She's been waiting for the geese all winter.
出其不意的偷袭很难奏效
Sneaking up unnoticed is impossible.
也许命运之神会眷顾勇敢的动物
Perhaps fortune will favour the bold.
雪雁的领地防御完善,很难让狐狸轻松下手
The colony is well-defended. There are no easy pickings here.
这只狐狸四处碰壁
She's driven away from every nest, but hunger compels her to continue.
但在饥饿的驱使下始终不肯放弃努力
There are more eggs here than she can possibly eat now.
这里的蛋多得它根本吃不了
But the nesting season is short.
但是雪雁的繁殖季很短
So she stashes much of her plunder for later in the year
所以狐狸会把蛋藏起来 以作雪雁迁徙之后的食物之用
when all the geese have gone.
在北极苔原更远的南边有更大的掠食动物出没
Further south, other bigger predators prowl the tundra.
狼
Wolves.
对于狼来说 在茫茫大草原上寻食甚至更为艰辛
For them, finding food on the plains is an even greater challenge.
不仅它们的猎物是季节性的,而且很难找到
Not only is their prey seasonal, it's also hard to find.
这些狼虽觅食多日 但一无所获
They've been searching for days without a sign.
在这无边无际的大地上的某处 有它们所需要的食物
Somewhere in this immense landscape there is food for them.
这就是了
This is it.
北美驯鹿
Caribou.
驯鹿日行30英里
Travelling 30 miles a day,
差不多整个夏季能够行进2000英里
they can cover nearly 2,000 miles during the summer months.
狼若找不到驯鹿 就会饿死
The wolves will starve if they don't find the caribou.
但若想找到这些 脚步永不停止的猎物又谈何容易？
But it's no easy task to locate prey that never stops travelling.
会叮咬它们的苍蝇以及为了寻找新草场, 驱使它们不停的向前迁徙
Biting flies and the quest for new pasture drives the migration ever onwards.
一头狼终于找到了猎物的痕迹
A wolf has finally picked up the trail.
驯鹿近在眼前
The caribou are close.
机会终于来了！
At last, a chance.
猎捕开始了
The hunt is on.
狼从受到惊吓的鹿群中寻找老弱孤残
The wolf panics the herd, and the weak and young are singled out.
一头小鹿和母亲失散了
A calf is separated from its mother.
在雪雁的领地,此时正值盛夏 小鸟正在孵化
At the goose colony, it's high summer and eggs are hatching.
让人惊讶的是所有的小雪雁 差不多都在一两天内出生
The young all emerge within a day or two, a marvel of timing.
现在 这片领地上一下子多出了上百万只小雪雁
The colony is now home to a million goslings.
这只狐狸还在拼命地收集食物
The fox is still gathering all she can get.
有时候 一张嘴根本就不够
Sometimes one mouth simply isn't enough.
总有一只难逃噩运
0ne will have to do.
不是所有的食物都要储藏起来
Not all food is stored.
有些马上就要吃
Some is needed right now.
这只母狐狸有七只饥饿的小狐狸要喂养
She has seven hungry cubs to feed.
随着小狐狸胃口不断增加
As their appetites grow,
母狐狸必须拼命觅食才能养活全家
the mother must work tirelessly to raise her family.
同时只有健康、饱满的小狐狸 才能捱过北极的寒冬
0nly fat, healthy cubs will survive the Arctic winter.
成千上万的小雪雁还在茁壮成长
The vast majority of the goslings are still flourishing.
它们强壮得可以旅行时, 父母马上就带着它们来到更为安全的水域
Their parents lead them down to the safety of the water as soon as they're strong enough to make the journey.
对于狐狸来说 美好时光已经接近尾声
For the foxes, boom time has come to an end.
但是母亲已经给了它们一个最好的开端
But the mother has given her cubs the best possible start in life.
雪雁还将一直在苔原上吃草
The geese will continue grazing the tundra
直到夏天结束 它们才会被迫南迁过冬
until the summer ends and they're forced to head south for the winter.
在这样的高纬度 阳光的强度非常微弱
At these latitudes, the sun's rays are weak
这里的草儿只有几个月的生长期
and grass can only grow here for a few months a year.
但是在更远的南边 夏天的时间更长,草原更加茂盛
But further south, summers are longer and the grasslands flourish.
北美大草原
The prairies of North America.
这里的大草原肥沃甘美 曾经养育着地球上最大的动物群落
This rich pasture once supported the greatest herds ever seen on our planet.
这里曾有六千万只北美野牛
There were once 60 million bison,
然而没有哪种动物能够幸免于人类的大捕杀
but no animal is immune to intensive hunting by man
野牛的栖息地也惨遭破坏
or the destruction of its habitat.
一百年前 野牛的数量曾锐减至不到一千
And a century ago, the bison were reduced to barely 1,000.
如今 幸亏制定了严厉的保护 这一物种的数量才得以逐步恢复
Now, thanks to rigorous protection, the species is recovering.
这里的草儿生长期很长
The growing season is long,
能够全年维系所有的动物群落的食物需要
and the grass here can support herds all year round.
公野牛重达一吨
Male bison weigh in at one ton.
在盛夏 公野牛个个吃得胖乎乎的
In high summer, the bulls are fat from the rich grazing
精神焕发.然而只有为数不多的公牛会和母牛交配
and in prime condition, but only a few will mate.
到底哪些可以交配很快就要决定了
Exactly which few is about to be decided.
在世界各个温带地区的草原上 夏季都是生长繁殖期
0n temperate plains around the world, summer is a time for growth and reproduction.
此时草花争艳
Now the grass produces its flowers.
万紫千红
New colours also come to the plains.
北方的开花季节跟南半球的草原互相呼应
The northern flowering is mirrored by the grasslands of the southern hemisphere,
天下最美丽动人的草原非南非的维尔德草原莫属
and nowhere is more impressive than on the veldt of South Africa.
并非所有温带地区的草原 在夏季都是如此五彩斑斓
Not all temperate plains are so rich and colourful in the summer.
这是西藏高原的仲夏
This is midsummer on the Tibetan plateau,
世界上海拔最高的草原
the highest great plain in the world.
在这样的环境里 依然生长着漫山遍野的草 维系所有食草动物的生存需要
Despite the conditions, grass survives and in sufficient quantities to support the highest of all grazing herds,
那些是野牦牛
those of the wild yak.
即使在夏天 日子也并不好过
Even in summer, life is hard.
温度几乎总是在零下 空气又非常地稀薄
Temperatures rarely rise above freezing and the air is thin.
而且这里又干燥异常,那是因为一个很大的原因
It's also exceptionally dry for one very big reason,
喜马拉雅
the Himalayas.
雄伟的山脉犹如一道高高的屏障
The great mountain range acts as a barrier,
阻挡了从南飘来的浮云 只在大地上投下了巨大雨影
preventing clouds moving in from the south, and this casts a giant rain shadow
西藏高原由此变得异常地干燥
that leaves Tibet high and dry.
即使风把土壤中仅存的水分带走 草也能存活下来.
Grass clings to life even as desiccating winds remove what little moisture remains in the soil.
只要草能够活下来
So long as grass can survive,
食草动物也能活下来
so can grazers.
藏野驴
Wild ass.
雄驴在争夺领地 最有实力的也最有可能得到雌驴的青睐
The males are fighting to win territories. Those that hold the best are more likely to attract a herd of females.
其实是闹着玩的
It's a frisky business.
那样算是胜了
That counts as a victory,
但却没有看到雌驴的出现
but he can't assume the females will actually turn up.
雌野驴是一种神秘的动物
Female asses are mysterious creatures.
随兴而来随兴而去 对于外人来说 这些雌驴的脾性好像是不可捉摸的
They come and go as they please and much of their behaviour seems unfathomable to an outsider.
它们是高原上的伟大游牧民族
They're the great nomads of the plateau
为了寻找绿洲
and will often trek vast distances across these parched plains
其足迹早己遍布整个西藏高原
in search of oases.
当这些野驴真地找到了新的天地
But when they do find paradise,
饮水的饮水 吃草的吃草 个个毫无留恋之情
they are liable to feed and drink for just a few hours
数小时后就绝尘而去
and then head back to the dust for no apparent reason.
野驴是高原边疆上最明显的拓荒者
Wild ass are the most conspicuous pioneers of this high frontier,
但数量最为可观的食草动物却深藏在地下
but the most numerous grazer in Tibet lives underground.
鼠兔 兔子的亲戚,和兔子一样以草为食
Pika, a relative of the rabbit. It, too, feeds on grass.
在毫无遮挡的草原上
0n the exposed plateau,
鼠兔从不敢远离自己的洞穴
pikas never stray far from their burrows.
可是尽管如此 鼠兔的洞穴还是经常被其它动物霸占
But even so, squatters will move in given half a chance.
然而尽管啄地鸟和雪雀鸠占雀巢的行为确实很讨厌
While ground peckers and snow finches can be a nuisance,
它们还是值得忍受的 它们可以在危险来临之前给鼠兔预先的警告
they're worth tolerating because they provide a valuable early warning system.
长相怪异的藏狐 鼠兔的灾星
The bizarre Tibetan fox. The pika's nemesis.
在蹑手蹑脚地潜近猎物时
When stalking, it keeps below the skyline,
藏狐能保持特别低的姿势 可能其古怪的体型起了一定的作用
perhaps helped by its curious body shape.
但是为什么是方形的头呢？
But why the square head?
在夏季
In summer,
西藏高原温度升高
the Tibetan plateau heats up,
南方的温湿空气随之而来
drawing in warm, wet air from the south.
可是雨水却从不光顾这里
But the water never arrives.
潮湿的空气上升遇到雄伟的喜马拉雅山后
As the moist air approaches, it's forced upwards by the Himalayas
便凝聚成为巨大的积雨云
and condenses into huge rain clouds.
雨全都下在喜马拉雅山南边的山峰上
These clouds drop all their water on the southern side of the mountains.
就是这些山峰的存在使得西藏变得气候干燥 也造成了季风雨只落在更远的南方
The very peaks that keep Tibet dry are responsible for the monsoon rains falling farther south
令印度的大地显得一片绿意盎然
and the greening of India.
在这里 伴着雨水的滋润,沐浴在灿烂的阳光下
Here, soaked by rain and bathed in tropical sun,
萋萋芳草生机无限
grass reaches its full potential.
象草是世界上最高的草
Elephant grass is the tallest in the world.
这种草长得比大象还高
Grass that towers over an elephant
里面可以隐藏各种各样的秘密
can conceal all sorts of surprises.
雄性孟加拉鸨
The male Lesser Florican.
在这么高的草丛里面求偶是很难得到关注的
It's hard work getting noticed when you go courting in high grass.
地处热带的印度 有着茂盛的草原
The long-grass plains of tropical India
草原上生活着世界上最大的
are home to some of the largest grass-eating mammals on our planet.
和最小的食草类哺乳动物
And some of the smallest.
姬猪的大小和兔子不相上下
Pygmy hogs are no bigger than rabbits.
这种猪是世界上最稀有的、体型最小的野猪
They're the tiniest and rarest of all wild pigs.
这只母猪正忙着把草收集起来
The female is busy collecting grass,
不过这不是为了填饱肚子
but not for eating.
而是为了筑巢
She's building a nest.
每一只小猪都小得可以放在手掌心上
Each piglet may be small enough to fit in the palm of a hand,
但母猪确生了有10只小猪
but she does have 10.
这里让我们见识到了如果有足够的阳光和雨水 草能够长到什么程度
This is how grass can grow, given unlimited sunshine and water.
然而地球上的绝大多数热带草原 在经历雨季后总是要经历旱季的
But on most tropical plains across our planet, the wet season is followed by a dry one.
在非洲的稀树大草原上
0n the African savannahs,
食草动物正浩浩荡荡地行进着 去寻找草和水
grazers are marching in search of grass and water.
由于缺乏雨水 这里的草原变成了黄尘地带
Without rain, these plains can become dust bowls.
草现在也许会被连根拔起
Grass can now lose its hold.
大象的生命变得岌岌可危 因为它们几乎每天都要喝水
Elephants are in immediate danger. They must drink almost daily.
在干渴的驱使下
Driven on by thirst,
它们在干涸的平原上跋涉几百英里
they march hundreds of miles across the parched plains.
领头的老雌象 凭着记忆 带领全家大小去寻找以前救过它们的水坑
Relying on memory, the matriarchs lead their families to those special water holes that saved them in previous years.
这个还有水
This one still has water,
可大象必须和其它照样渴得要命的动物
but they must share what remains
分享所剩无几的资源
with desperately thirsty animals of all kinds.
这时候正是紧张时刻
These are tense times.
大象在这些水坑的控制权上占主导地位 但随着夜幕降临力量的对比将发生变化
The elephants dominate the water hole, but as night falls the balance of power will shift.
口干舌焦的动物趁着夜色纷至沓来
Thirsty herds continue to arrive throughout the night.
夜间行路比较凉爽
It's a cooler time to travel.
在黑暗之中 局势发生了变化
In the darkness, the tables turn.
大象的夜视能力只比人类稍好一点
The elephant's night vision is little better than our own.
而狮子有着更加锐利的视力
But lions have much more sensitive eyes.
狮子十分饥饿 大象好像也感觉到了危机
The cats are hungry and the elephants seem to sense it.
狮子通常不会把大象当作捕杀对象
Lions don't usually hunt elephants,
但到了走投无路之时也会铤而走险
but desperate times require desperate measures.
这一象群里有更容易下手的幼象
This herd contains calves, easier targets.
但是怎样才能接近呢？
But how to reach them?
成年象已经围成圈在保护小象
The adults encircle their young.
这堵灰色皮墙围得非常坚固 很难突破
It's an impenetrable wall of grey.
还有一些筋疲力竭的落伍的大象赶了过来
A few exhausted stragglers are still arriving.
其中一头落单了
0ne of them is alone.
但是由于它的体型太大了 狮子对付不了
But it's too big for the lions to tackle.
这头看起来小一点
This one looks a little smaller.
一只单枪匹马的狮子是根本没有办法的
A solitary lion stands no chance,
但是现在整个狮群都已倾巢出动
but the whole pride is here.
它们有三十只之多 如此的数量就变成了捕杀大象的专家
There are 30 of them and they are specialist elephant hunters.
这头大象足以供整群狮子至少吃一周
This elephant will feed the whole pride for at least a week.
大象知道这里的水坑很危险
Elephants know these drinking holes are dangerous,
但没有办法
but they have no choice.
刚刚播放的残酷的画面提醒着我们 水对于草原上的生命是何等重要啊
The dramas that play out here are a savage reminder of how important water is for all life on these plains.
旱季接近尾声
As the dry season finally draws to a close,
经受了太阳烘烤的非洲稀树大草原 发生了天翻地覆的变化
Africa's baked savannahs undergo a radical change.
大雨横扫整个非洲大地 于是生命力极其顽强的草 又复活了
Rain sweeps across the continent and grass, the great survivor, rises again.
动物又成群结队而来
And the herds return.
这些动物曾接连数月 守着零落四方的小水坑 过着艰难的生活
For months they've been scattered over huge areas, clinging to existence around tiny water holes.
现在好时光又来了
Now, the good times are back.
有一些地方非常特别
A few African savannahs are very special.
在这些平坦的草原上 四面八方的雨水汇聚在一起
Here, rainwater from far and wide flows across the flat plains.
草被淹在水里 却依然生长
Grass is submerged, but still it grows.
洪水淹不死 大火烧不死 烈日晒不死 冰雪冻不死
Flooded, burnt, baked and frozen,
草能承受一切的苦难
grass can withstand it all.
六个月的旱季过后 如茵的绿草再一次覆盖了尘嚣大地
After six months of drought, grass replaces dust over great areas.
小草发芽了 动物们全都闻风而来
Fresh new shoots draw animals from great distances.
很多动物都不远万里前来 美好的时光谁也不愿错过
Many undertake epic migrations to catch the boom time.
还有一些有本领的动物一年到头就生活在这里
Some resourceful animals live here all the year round.
狒狒就是长年居住在这里的
Baboons are permanent residents,
但若想在这块刚被洪水淹没的草原上觅食 狒狒也得改变自己的习性
but they have to change their behaviour if they are to gather what they need on the newly flooded plains.
这里到处都有吃的 但要到手还真有点棘手
There's plenty to eat, but getting to it can be a little uncomfortable.
虽然水给小家伙们带来了新的麻烦
New water poses problems for the youngsters,
但是它们知道要怎么才能找个干燥的位子
but they know where to find a dry seat.
为了鲜美多汁的蜗牛把爪子弄湿也值得
Ajuicy snail is ample recompense for sodden paws.
经历了干旱贫脊之后 动物们现在可以享受成果了.
Having survived the dry, barren times, animals can now reap the rewards.
在这个四季分明的行星上
0n this seasonal planet,
大草原是盛宴与饥荒并存之地
the great plains are lands of feast and famine.
在其生长旺盛期 大草原能维系地球上最大的生命群落
At their peak, they support the greatest gatherings of wildlife found anywhere on Earth.